# **Eliane Fortes | Software Engineer**

Melbourne - Australia • 0405 097 837

<u>elimrfortes@gmail.com</u> • <u>linkedin.com/in/eliane-fortes</u> • <u>github.com/elifortes</u>



# **PROFILE**

Passionate Software Engineer with a comprehensive foundation in full-stack development, gained from Le Wagon's Web Development bootcamp, and a strong background in business analysis and customer service.

Skilled in creating customer-centric solutions using technologies like JavaScript, React, Node.js, and Ruby on Rails, complemented by practical experience in HTML/CSS, Bootstrap, and database management (SQL/NoSQL).

My previous roles as a Support Worker and Business Analyst have honed my problem-solving, analytical, and organizational skills, ensuring a user-focused approach to software development. With projects ranging from an Airbnb-inspired boat rental platform to a groupgifting web app, I have demonstrated my ability to innovate and execute within collaborative environments.

Graduated in Business Administration and furthered my analytical skills through a Data Analytics course at General Assembly, I am driven to apply my diverse skill set and fresh perspectives to contribute to a forward-thinking software development.

#### My skills include:

- JavaScript - HTML/CSS - Ruby on Rails - Bootstrap - React.js - Node.js - Express.js - SQL

- GitHub - Heroku - Customer Service

# **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

#### **Support Worker | Discover Nursing Australia**, Sydney

Jan 2018 - Aug 2023

- Provided exceptional customer service, emphasizing empathy, and understanding.
- Addressed and resolved client queries effectively, indicating strong problem-solving skills and customer-focused service.
- Coordinated care consultations, reflecting excellent organizational and timemanagement abilities.

# Business Analyst | Valeo Thermal Bus Systems, Caxias do Sul/Brazil

Jun 2016 – Sep 2017

- Conducted regular statistical report generation, emphasizing analytical skills and attention to detail.
- Analysis and negotiation of orders and delivery schedules with customers.
- Responsible for monitoring daily revenue and meeting targets.
- Participation in the qualification of processes, identifying and applying innovations and differentiated solutions, and validating the applicability of new technologies, knowledge, and practices.

# Business Analyst | Keko, Caxias do Sul/Brazil

Feb 2012 – May 2016

- Conducted regular statistical report generation, emphasizing analytical skills and attention to detail.
- Analysis and negotiation of orders and delivery schedules with customers.
- Responsible for monitoring daily revenue and meeting targets.

# **EDUCATION**

# Web Developer Bootcamp | Le Wagon, Melbourne

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Completed a 9-week full-time intensive coding bootcamp.
- Applied practical knowledge of HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, GitHub, Heroku and Ruby on Rails.
- Developed and Airbnb-inspired boat rental platform.
- Proposed and developed the web app 'Gift Genius', completing the project within 2 weeks as part of a 3-person team.

# The Ultimate IT Beginners - From 0 to Junior Engineer | TechWorld with Nana Sep 2023 - Sep 2023

- Gained hands-on experience in the full Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), enhancing understanding of software development and release workflows.
- Developed a simple web application integrating frontend, backend, and database using a comprehensive tech stack including HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Vue.js, Node.js, Express.js, and MongoDB.
- Acquired foundational knowledge in infrastructure management, including virtual server creation and configuration on cloud platforms.

### Data Analytics Bootcamp | General Assembly, Sydney

Apr 2022 – Jul 2022

- Applied practical knowledge of Tableau, PostgreSQL, and Excel.
- Delivered a project analysing Chicago City Council phone requests and provide a detailed examination of complaints by the councilperson elected to represent the area.

**Bachelor of Management Administration | UCS, Caxias do Sul/Brazil** 

Mar 2010 - Jul 2017